Jean-Baptiste Bohiki

jbbohiki@gmail.com • https://flemking.vercel.app • +22999544569

CARRIER OBJECTIVE

Web developer with 5+ years of experience, currently working part-time as a WordPress engineer for WPBuffs(a US based company). I am confident that the skills and experience I have gained over the past 5 years will make me an ideal candidate. I would like to bring to your company the qualities that my previous employers have found in me: versatile skills, quick learning, integrity, results-oriented, works smart, and a willingness to always satisfy clients.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WordPress Engineer oct. 2021 - Present

WPBUFFS

- · Work alongside fellow developers to achieve individual, and more importantly, team goals.
- Contribute to the maintenance, monitoring and securing of 700+ websites.
- · Perform daily checks and troubleshoot issues on our clients' websites.
- · Perform weekly updates for 10+ websites.
- Deliver exceptional results in a timely manner.
- · Get clients to leave positive reviews for the company on Google and Trustpilot.
- · Several times, I was able to solve some websites issues that even our most competent developers could not solve.

Web Developer oct. 2017 - Present

Freelance

- · Write and maintain python scripts.
- · Consult with clients to develop and document website requirements.
- · Prepare mock-ups and storyboards.
- Create client side applications and web sites that meet customer requirements.
- Manage Projects and understand project constraints (deadlines, budget, expectations).
- Master CMS tools (Wordpress, Webflow, Shopify), Framework and code editing tools: Next JS, Django, VS Code...
- Design and develop a website: design, modeling and architecture of applications, methods, standards, languages and development tools, web programming languages, standards and security procedures...

EDUCATION AND CERITIFICATIONS

Google IT Automation with Python Professional Certificate	aug. 2022 - oct. 2022
Google	

Agile with Atlassian Jira Certificate jul. 2022 - aug. 2022

Atlassian University

Google

Google IT Support Professional Certificate jun. 2022 - aug. 2022

Frontend Developer Carrier Path may. 2021 - jul. 2021 Scrimba

This program contains 14 modules. All modules are filled with interactive coding challenges to ensure effective learning. It has helped me to strengthen my skills in: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, User Interface Design(UI Design), etc.

Computer Science 50 jan. 2021 - jul. 2021

Harvard University

Taught by David J. Malan, CS50x has taught me how to think algorithmically and solve problems efficiently. Topics covered include abstraction, algorithms, data structures, encapsulation, resource management, security, software engineering and web development. The languages used are C, Python, SQL JavaScript, as well as CSS and HTML. The

problems are inspired by real-world domains such as biology, cryptography, finance, forensics, and gaming.

One year of university in economic statistics

ENEAM • Cotonou, Benin

Due to several circumstances, I was not able to complete my degree, but I have retained his sense of statistical analysis which I apply when analyzing Google Analytics data and my clients' advertising campaigns.

High School Diploma

oct. 2016 - jul. 2017

dec. 2017 - jan. 2019

CSS / CED • Cotonou, Benin

SKILLS

- Python / CSS / JAVASCRIPT / React.js / Next.js / TailwindCSS / SASS / PHP / MySQL / APIs
- WordPress / WebFlow / Shopify / Bubble / SEO
- Jira / Agile Management / Project Management
- Figma / Adobe XD / Adobe Photoshop
- UX / UI Design
- · Creation and optimization of advertising campaigns
- · Ability to adapt
- Autonomy
- Sense of responsibility
- Teamwork
- · Decision-making skills
- · Ability to quickly analyze and solve problems

LANGUAGES

French: NativeEnglish: Advanced